In the last episode we have created our first full stack buffer overflow exploit, by overwriting
在上一集中，我们首次来了个栈缓存溢出漏洞的完整实践，
the return pointer on the stack and jumping to shellcode that we have placed on the stack
通过覆盖栈上的返回指针，并跳转到
as well.
我们放置在栈上的 shellcode
In this episode we will look at stack level 6 which looks at what happens when you have
在本集中，我们将查看第6层栈，
restrictions on the return address.
它会查看当您有返回地址的限制，会发生什么。
To understand this video you must have understood how a normal buffer overflow and jumping to
要理解此视频，您必须了解正常缓冲区溢出和跳向 Shellcode
shellcode works.
是怎么工作的。
I hope I explained it well enough in the past videos.
我希望我在过去的视频中，解释得足够好。
But if there are still open questions, please post them on reddit.
但如果还有未解决的问题，请将其张贴到 Reddit上。
I really need you to have understood that stuff.
我真的需要你，能够理解之前哪些东西，不然下面没法继续。
As a hint this level tells us that,
提示，关于这一级告诉我们，
This level can be done in a couple of ways, such as finding the duplicate of the payload
它可以用两种方法完成，例如，查找有效负载的副本
(objdump -s), or ret2libc, or even return orientated programming.
（objdump -s），或 ret2libc，甚至面向返回编程。
In this video we will not be able to explore return oriented programming.
在本视频中，我们将无法探索面向返回编程。
But I will show you a couple of other tricks that will eventually lead to return oriented
但是，我会给你看一些其他的，
programming.
最终会导致面向返回编程的技巧。
So let’s have a look at the source code.
让我们来看一下源代码。
And again, it’s very similar to the previous levels, just some small changes.
同样，它与之前的级别非常相似，只是有一些小的变化。
Instead of everything being in main, main calls this function get_path.
不是所有东西都在 mina 中，main 调用这个函数 get_path。
Get path allocates a string buffer for 64 characters.
得到 path 分配了 64个字符的字符串缓冲区。
Then reads a string with gets.
然后，用 gets 读取字符串。
And we all know by now that with gets we can read arbitrarily many characters, which we
我们现在都知道，用 gets 我们可以任意地读取许多字符，
can use to overwrite the return pointer on the stack.
以此，我们可用来，覆盖栈上的返回指针。
But the next line is interesting.
但下一行代码很有趣。
__builtin_return_address is a function from the compiler, which you can use to read the
__builtin_return_address 是编译器中的一个函数，
current return address from the stack.
您可以使用它来读取，栈的当前返回地址。
And this return address is checked if it starts with hex 0xbf.
如果返回地址，以 hex 0xbf 开头，则检查该返回地址。
The ampersand performs a bitwise AND with the address.
这个符号，会对地址，执行“与(AND)”位操作。
After that only the part where they were same survives.
在操作之后，只有他们相同的部分，存活下来。
basically setting the remaining bits to 0.
基本上来说，剩余的位都成了 0。
And checking if the front is still hex bf.
检查前面是否，仍然是 hex bf 。
If the return address starts with 0xbf, it prints this return address and exits.
如果返回地址以 0xbf 开头，则打印此返回地址，并退出。
When we use our exploit from last time.
当我们使用上次的漏洞脚本时。
And adjust the padding to account for the new unsigned int in this function, we see
并调整填充，去解释这个函数中，新的无符号int，
that it doesn’t work.
我们看到它不起作用。
It fails with bzzzt.
bzzzt 失败了。
Ok.
好吧。
So we cannot use addresses that start with hex bf.
所以，我们不能使用以 hex bf开头的地址。
The exit protects this function from being exploited that way.
退出保护这个函数，不被这样滥用。
Because the exit is a syscall that simply quits the program.
因为 exit 是一个系统调用，只是简单地退出程序。
So even though we have smashed the return pointer, this function will never return.
所以，即使我们破坏了返回指针，这个函数也不会返回。
So you can see, that even having a buffer overflow doesn’t necessarily mean you can
这样，你就可以看到，即使有一个缓冲区溢出，也不一定意味着
exploit it.
你可以利用它。
When we open this level now in gdb, break at getpath, run it and then look at the mapped
当我们现在在gdb中，打开这个级别时，在 getpath 时中断，运行它，
memory with `info proc map`.
然后，用“info proc map”查看映射内存。
We can see that the only addresses that start with bf are on the stack.
我们可以看到，只有以 bf 开头的地址在栈上。
So basically we cannot return to a stack address.
所以基本上，我们不能返回到栈地址。
This is crazy, then how can we run our code, if we cannot return to the stack where we
我去，那我们怎么运行我们的(漏洞)代码，如果，
place our shellcode?
我们不能返回到栈中，我们代码的放置位置？
So first of all, we can still control the return pointer.
打起精神来，所以首先，我们仍然可以控制返回指针。
As long as it doesn’t start with bf.
只要不是从 bf 开始的就行。
And now comes this sick idea, of returning into known code.
现在出现了一个大胆的想法，关于返回到已知的代码中。
Let’s think about this.
让我们想想。
The return instruction just looks at the current address on top of the stack, removes it, and
返回指令，只查看栈顶部的当前地址，将其移除，
just jumps there.
然后就跳到那里。
… What would happen if you return to the address 0x080484f9.
… 那如果您返回地址 0x080484f9 会发生什么。
Which is the return instruction itself.
也就是返回指令本身。
Think about this.
想想这个。
We overwrite the return pointer with hex 0x080.
我们用 hex 0x080 覆盖返回指针。
We reach the return instruction, it will pop this address from the stack and jump to it.
我们到达返回指令，它将从栈中弹出这个地址，并跳转到它。
Basically just jump to itself.
可以说是，跳到自己身上。
And now it will read the next address on the stack and jump there.
现在，它将读取栈上的下一个地址，并跳到那里。
Now you could repeat that.
现在，你可以重复一遍。
Make the next address on the stack again 0x080.
再次，将栈上的下一个地址设置为0x080。
Or place the address of the stack here.
或者把栈的地址，放在这里。
And we can return into the stack again.
我们可以，再次返回到了栈中。
And in theory that should work.
从理论上讲，这是可行的。
Because the original return address got overwritten with an address that starts with 0x080.
因为原始返回地址，被以0x080开头的地址覆盖。
Ok let’s try that.
好吧，我们试试看。
let’s modify our exploit code.
让我们修改我们的漏洞代码。
Instead of the shellcode let’s use int 3, CC instruction again.
我们不再使用shellcode，而是使用 int 3，cc 指令。
For a trap.
制造一个陷阱。
We all know now that when we hit them, we have code execution and we just have to find
我们现在都知道，当我们触碰它们时，我们要有代码执行，而我们只需要找到
suitable shellcode.
合适的 shellcode。
So let’s focus on the interesting part.
所以，让我们集中在有趣的部分。
Set a breakpoint at the return of getpath, and then run it with our exploit input.
在getpath的返回处，设置一个断点，然后使用我们的漏洞输入，运行它。
We hit the breakpoint.
我们到达了断点。
And we got past the return pointer check.
我们通过了，返回指针的检查。
So let’s look at the stack ourselves.
那么，让我们现在看看这个栈。
We can see that the address on top of the stack is now the 0x080.
我们可以看到栈顶部的地址，现在是0x080。
Which is the return instruction.
这是返回指令。
So now single step forward.
所以，现在前进一步。
This should pop this address from the stack and jump there.
就应该是从栈中弹出这个地址，并跳转到那里。
And indeed.
确实如此。
We hit the breakpoint again, because we jumped to itself.
我们又碰到了断点，因为我们跳到了自己身上。
When you now look at the stack, the next address on the stack is the stack address.
现在查看栈时，栈上的下一个地址，是这个栈地址。
And we will return into this address now.
我们现在，就返回到这个地址。
So when we just continue, we will return into the stack, like in the previous exploit, where
因此，当我们继续时，我们将返回到栈中，就像在前面的漏洞中一样，
we hit our traps.
我们击中了陷阱。
Boom!
开花！
Arbitrary code execution!
任意代码执行(漏洞完成)！
By the way.
顺便说一句。
This address where we jumped to, the 0x080 is a gadget.
我们跳到的这个地址，0x080是一个小工具。
When you read about return oriented programming, you are looking for gadgets.
当你读到关于面向返回的编程时，对小工具有所了解后。
And that was a simple no operation gadget.
会发现，这就是一个简单的，无操作的小工具。
It was just a return, doing nothing.
这只是一个返回(操作)，就什么都不做了。
And for full return oriented programming, you look for gadgets that do some more stuff,
对于完整的面向返回编程，你能寻找，能做更多事情的小工具，
before returning to the next address.
在返回下一个地址之前。
Now when we do this kind of stuff, you hear me saying “return into”, or “jump to”.
现在，当我们做这种事情的时候，你听到我说“返回到(return into)”，或者“跳到（jump to)”。
Those become equivalent in this case.
在这种情况下，它们是等价的。
Because yes, we execute a return instruction, but we are not returning to the original function
虽然是的，我们执行一个返回指令，但不再
anymore.
没有返回到原始函数。
We are returning into something else.
我们，又返回到了别的地方。
Effectively just jumping somewhere else.
实际上，只是跳到别的地方。
So I hope that doesn’t confuse you.
所以，我希望，这不会困惑你。
Let’s have a look at another trick.
让我们看一看，另一个技巧。
It’s very similar to what we did in stack level 4.
这与我们在第4层栈中，所做的非常相似。
So where else could we jump to.
那么，我们还能跳到哪里呢？
One of the
其中一个提示是，
hints said we could look into ret2libc.
说我们可以调查 ret2libc。
Now that you are almost a pro in exploitation, you understand what that means.
既然你现在，几乎是漏洞行家，你就会明白，这意味着什么了。
Return into libc.
返回到 libc。
Like we just returned into some code, we could also return into the huge library libc.
就像我们刚刚返回到，某些代码一样，我们也可以返回到，巨大库 libc中。
There must be something interesting that we could abuse.
一定有什么有趣的东西，我们可以利用的。
One interesting function from libc is system.
libc中，一个有趣的函数是system。
Which executes a shell command.
它执行shell命令。
With print system, we can find the address of it.
通过 print system，我们可以找到它的地址。
But simply returning into it will probably not work.
但是简单地返回到它，可能不会起作用。
We need to make sure to control a couple of things.
我们需要确保控制一些事情。
Let’s create a simple C program that calls the libc system for us.
让我们创建一个简单的C程序，它为我们调用libc system
In the end we want to somehow execute system with /bin/sh.
最后，我们希望以某种方式，使用 /bin/sh 执行 system。
Because then we get a shell.
因为这样，我们就有了shell。
If we try that here, that works well.
如果我们在这里试一下，效果很好。
Now let’s look at this in gdb.
现在让我们在 gdb 中看看。
We can see that before the call to system, the address of the command we want to execute
我们可以看到，在调用 system 之前，我们要执行的命令的地址，
is put on top of the stack.
是放在栈的顶部。
And as we know, a call to a function will push the return address on to the stack as
如我们所知，对函数的一次调用(call)，会把返回地址放在栈上
well.
好。
So if we draw this, this is how the stack will look like once we are at the start of
因此，如果我们画出这个，就是当 system 开始时，
system.
栈的样子。
First the address of the command is placed on the stack.
首先，命令的地址放在栈上。
And then the address we want to return to.
然后，是我们要返回的地址。
Now imagine if we use our buffer overflow to return into system.
现在想象一下，如果使用我们的缓冲区溢出，返回到 system 中。
Firstof all we didn’t execute a call instruction.
首先，我们没有执行一个 call 指令。
Thus there was no return address pushed.
因此，不会推入返回地址。
But we fully control the stack.
但是，我们完全控制了栈。
So system expects the stack to look like this.
所以 system 希望，栈看起来像这样。
And we can build this by hand!
我们可以手工建造(栈的样子)！
So first we have to put the return address for system on the stack.
所以首先，我们必须将 system 的返回地址放在栈上。
But actually we don’t care about this right now.
但实际上，我们现在不在乎这个。
But that is still cool and important, and remember that.
但这仍也很重要，还很雕，要记住这一点。
Because you can chain those things together.
因为你可以把这些东西，连在一起。
Like we chained two returns after each other before, we could chain multiple function calls
就像我们以前一个接一个地链接了两个返回(指针)，我们可以
or other gadgets after each other, by always controlling the return pointer of the next
把多个函数调用或其他小工具连起来，具体做法是，
step.
通过始终控制下一步的返回指针。
So in our case, when system finishes, we will run into a segfault, because it will return
所以在我们的例子中，当 system 完成时，我们会运行到一个segfault，
into 0x41414141.
因为它会返回到 0x41414141。
the next address on the stack has to be a string we want to execute.
栈上的下一个地址，必须是我们要执行的字符串。
Preferably “/bin/sh”.
最好是“/bin/sh”。
There are many options how to get a reference to such a string.
此类获取一个引用的字符串，其实有许多选项。
one option would be to use a stack address.
一种选择是，使用栈地址。
Because there are strings we control.
因为会有我们控制的字符串。
Or environment variables.
或环境变量。
Because they are at the bottom of the stack and a bit easier to predict.
因为它们位于栈的底部，并且更容易预测。
But as you remember, the stack is a bit unreliable and shifting around.
但是，正如您所记得的，这个栈有点不可靠，而且会四处移动。
A more reliable technique is this here.
这里有一种更可靠的技术。
We can use find to search in the mapped memory of libc for a string.
我们可以使用 find ，在 libc 的映射内存中，搜索字符串。
Cool, apparently at this address we can find /bin/sh.
很雕，显然在这个地址，我们可以找到 /bin/sh。
Let’s check if that is true.
我们来看看，这是不是真的。
Examine memory as string at this address.
在此地址以字符串形式，检查内存。
Awesome!
酷！
What the frak! gdb.
WTF！gdb。
What the hell are you doing.
你到底在干什么？
Why do you say you found bin/sh there, if it’s not there?
你为什么说，你在那里找到了 bin/sh，如果没有呢？
I have no idea why this happens.
我不知道为什么会这样。
Couldn’t find anything online.
在网上，找不到任何东西。
Anyway.
不管怎样。
Ignore this.
忽略这一点。
Here is another technique.
这是另一种技术。
We can use strings to find all strings in libc.
我们可以使用 strings，来查找libc 中的所有字符串。
And with -t we can print the offset inside this file as hex.
使用 -t，我们可以将文件中的偏移量，打印为 hex 。
And then we can simply add this offset to the address libc is loaded to.
然后我们可以简单地把这个偏移量，添加到 libc 加载到的地址。
And that is the real address of /bin/sh.
这是 /bin/sh 的真实地址。
Ok so let’s copy this address into our exploit.
好吧，让我们把这个地址，复制到我们的漏洞脚本中。
And then let’s try it.
然后我们试试看。
Remember to use the trick from the previous video with the parenthesis and cat.
记住要用上一个视频中，带括号和cat的技巧。
Because the exploit script will close the input again.
因为漏洞脚本，将再次关闭输入(input)。
And cool!
酷！
It works.
它起作用了。
What we just did was the technique called ret2libc.
我们刚刚做的是一种叫做 ret2libc 的技术。
And we never executed any code on the stack!
而且我们从未在栈上，执行过任何代码！
Maybe you ask yourself why the hell the stack was executable in the first place.
也许你会问自己，为什么TMD，这个栈一开始是可执行的。
There is no valid reason why the stack should be executable.
栈是可执行的，是不合理的。
That’s why there exists a general memory policy nowadays.
这就是为什么，现在有一个通用的内存策略。
Write xor Execute.
Wirte xor Execute。
Basically it means, never have a memory page that is writeable AND executable.
基本上，它意味着，永远不会有可写和可执行的内存页。
Because then an attacker cannot execute any shellcode that he was able to write in the
因为这样攻击者，就不能执行任何 shellcode，
process memory.
因为，不能写入进程内存。
So we would hope that today every modern system uses DEP, data execution prevention and sets
因此，我们希望今天每个现代 system ，都使用DEP、数据执行预防和
the NX bit, the non executable bit for memory pages like the stack.
设置 nx 位，是内存页（如栈）的不可执行位。
But reality is not so simple.
但现实，并非如此简单。
Embedded devices are on the rise with the Internet of Things, and often they don’t
随着物联网的兴起，嵌入式设备也在兴起，
support features like that.
但它们通常不会支持这样的功能。
Or modern programming languages like javascript use JIT.
或像 javascript 这样的现代编程语言使用JIT。
Just in time compiler.
实时编译器（Just in time compiler）。
So they have to compile code on the fly in memory when needed and execute that.
因此，当需要时，他们必须在内存中，即时编译代码并执行它。
So they need writeable and executable memory regions.
因此，它们需要可写和可执行的内存区域。
But even if we had DEP, we could use techniques like ret2libc to never execute actual shellcode,
但是，即使我们有DEP，我们也可以使用像 ret2libc 这样的漏洞技术，不需要执行实际的 shellcode，
but still pwn a system.
但仍然需要一个 system。
And at some point in the future, I will make a video about return oriented programming.
在将来的某个时候，我会制作一个关于面向返回编程的视频。
Which is the next advanced step for this kind of technique.
这是这种技术的，下一个高级形态。